**Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy covers noyb.eu, support.noyb.eu and the noyb.eu newsletters.

**(1) When you browse our main page** [**https://noyb.eu**](https://noyb.eu/ "https://noyb.eu/")

**In brief:** We provide you with this page, make sure it stays secure and get an anonymous statistic to see if we succeeded in doing so.  
**Purpose:** We process your personal data for two purposes: (A) to provide this page to you (“_traffic data_” such as your IP address) and (B) to use your personal data for ensuring the security of the page.  
**Storage:** (A) Traffic data is not stored. (B) Security log data (e.g. when the software identifies an “incident”) are deleted within 6 months, unless there is a particular reason to keep information for a longer period of time (e.g. individual IP addresses are blocked).  
**Legal Basis:** (A) Your consent to receive our page and (B) our legitimate interests (for security reasons we process personal information, IP addresses, on this page) in maintaining the security of our page and fulfilling our legal duty to keep the page secure.  
**Processors:** We may use trustworthy processors that only process your personal data on our behalf (“processors”). The particular provider may be subject to change over time. Currently all our core systems, including our website, are hosted on our own servers. Some elements that relate to newsletters are hosted by dialog-Mail eMarketing Systems GmbH (details below at 3) on our behalf.  
**Other** **Recipients:** Usually none. The only exception can be our external backend support (nycro UG, Hütten 118, 20355 Hamburg, Germany) that can have unavoidable access to information when solving technical issues.  
**Third Country Transfers:** None. We process your data within the EEA/EU.  
**Cookies:** We do not use cookies on noyb.eu.  
**Statistics:** In addition to the processing above, we run a statistics system that does not process any personal data.

**(2) Additional processing when you become a supporting member and use** [**https://support.noyb.eu**](https://support.noyb.eu/ "https://support.noyb.eu/")

**In brief:** In addition to the processing described under (1), we process the data that is necessary for managing your _noyb_ membership, such as administering payments and mailings.  
**More Details:** If you become a supporting member, we store the data you have provided in the online forms. We generate a member ID number once you join. We are also legally required to generate a timestamp recording when you join _noyb_ as a member. If you join as a member we store your IP address for reasons of fraud prevention. We keep a record of any changes you make to your membership data to be able to manage the account. This data is only stored in order to manage your membership (the contract between us).  
**Purpose:** The management of your membership and for regular updates via email.  
**Storage:** All data is deleted, should you not complete the sign-up process (“timeout”). If you become a _noyb_ member, your information is kept for the duration of your membership and you can change it at any time by logging in on [https://support.noyb.eu/](https://support.noyb.eu/ "https://support.noyb.eu/"). If you terminate your membership Austrian accounting provisions require 7 years of bookkeeping. There may be other individual situations or exceptional legitimate interests (e.g. if you file a legal claim against us) that would require us to process your personal data furhter, but cannot be forseen.  
**Legal Basis:** In order to enter into and continue performing the contract between our members and us, legal obligations resulting from your membership, and our legitimate interests.  
**Legitimate Interests:** For reasons of fraud prevention we process personal information (IP addresses) and may process data in cases of legal disputes stemming from a membership.  
**Processors:** We may use trustworthy processors that only process your personal data on our behalf (“processors”). The particular provider may be subject to change over time. Currently all our core systems, including our member system, are hosted on our own servers.  
**Payment Providers:** If you choose to pay via credit card, you will be forwarded to a secure page of SIX Payment Services Austria GmbH and/or your payment provider that is not under our control (e.g. the 3D Secure Code form by your issuing bank).You can find the SIX privacy information [here](https://www.six-payment-services.com/en/services/legal/privacy-statement.html "Current Document"). Our bank (Erste Bank der oesterreichischen Sparkassen AG, Am Belvedere 1, 1100 Wien, for SEPA payments) needs to receive the relevant transaction information if you choose SEPA payment.  
**Postal Service:** If you do not opt-out from reciving a welcome gift, your address will be used to deliver the welcome gift via the postal service.  
**Other Recipients:** Usually none. The only exceptions are (1) our external technical support (nycro UG, Hütten 118, 20355 Hamburg, Germany) that can have unavoidable access to information when solving technical issues and (2) the Austrian tax authority, but only if you choose that we report your membership fee or donation to have this deducted from your Austrian taxes.  
**Third Country Transfers:** None. We process your data within the EEA/EU.  
**Cookies:** We use a session cookie (named “session”), to process your membership application, which holds a random string. It is deleted when you close your browser.

**(3) Additional Processing when you sign up to _noyb_ newsletters**

**In brief:** In addition to the processing described under (1), we use your email to send you the requested newsletter(s) and any additional data you have provided when signing up.  
**Purpose:** Sending you our newsletter and customize elements in newsletters (like country-specific information).  
**Storage:** Your data is removed from the mailing list when you cancel your subscription. Your personal data is consequently deleted within 24 hours.  
**Legal Basis:** Your consent for sending emails.  
**Processors:** We only use trustworthy third parties that only process your personal data on our behalf (“processors”). For mailing we currently use dialog-Mail eMarketing Systems GmbH. The particular provider may be subject to change over time.  
**Other Recipients:** Usually none. The only exception can be our external backend support (nycro UG, Hütten 118, 20355 Hamburg, Germany) that can have unavoidable access to information when solving technical issues.  
**Third Country Transfers:** None. We process your data within the EEA/EU.  
**Cookies:** We use a session cookie (named “PHPSESSID”), to process your signup, which holds a random string. It is deleted when you close your browser.  

**(4) Additional Processing when you share our page on external networks or follow links**

**It’s simple:** We currently cannot really guarantee other people’s compliance – but working on this issue is exactly the purpose of _noyb_!  
**More Details:** If you click on any button that allows you to share our page (e.g. Twitter or Facebook) or follow a link to a third party page, you will be redirected to this other page; you are then subject to the privacy policy of this third party. We currently cannot guarantee these third parties’ compliance with the GDPR – but with your help we are working on their GDPR compliance too!  

**(5) When you send us a message via our ticket system**

**It’s simple:** If you send us an general request (e.g. via our webform or at our general email address) your emails go into a ticket system. Our team will then assign the ticket to a colleague and you will get an answer from us.  
**Purpose:** Assigning the ticket to a team member and responding to your request.  
**Storage:** Tickets are automatically deleted within 6 months from the last communication, unless there is a legal duty to keep the ticket, such as accounting regulations or keeping evidence of legal requests.  
**Legal Basis:** Your consent when sending us an email ("affirmative action" when sending an email to a recipient) and, in certain cases, our legitimate interest or legal duty to keep communication as evidence.  
**Processors:** We may use trustworthy processors that only process your personal data on our behalf (“processors”). The particular provider may be subject to change over time. Currently all our core systems, including our ticket system, are hosted on our own servers.  
**Other Recipients:** Usually none. The only exception can be our external backend support (nycro UG, Hütten 118, 20355 Hamburg, Germany) that can have unavoidable access to information when solving technical issues.  
**Third Country Transfers:** None. We process your data within the EEA/EU.  

**(6) In all cases, you have the following rights**

**It’s simple:** Just send us a message at [info@noyb.eu](mailto:info@noyb.eu "mailto:info@noyb.eu") and we’ll take care of things!  
**More Details:** You have the right to access, to rectify, to erasure, to object, to restrict processing, to data portability, to withdraw your consent and to launch a complaint with your local data protection authority. We are governed by the Austrian data protection authority (“Datenschutzbehörde”).
